American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIi. 1897 APS.Archives.IIi APS.Archives.IIi
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 5, 1897; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922
    Stanford University, A.L.S. 1p. Encs. wanting Sends drawings for Ashley's paper on Arkansas geology. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 217-318.
  - Letter to J[sic] M[inis] Hays, June 5, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Boston Book Company
    Boston, Typed L. on postal card 1p. and add. Has no volumes of National Geographic.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 5, 1897; 7-3/4x5; Hayden, Lewis S.
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Can provide issues of "Insect Life."
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 6, 1897; 10-1/4x8-1/4; Royal Scottish Society of Arts
    Edinburgh, A.L.S: W[illiam] Fraser 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 8, 1897; 14x8-1/2; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Enc.wanting. Sends part of MS. of his paper on excavations in Florida. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 8, 1897; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Museo de La Plata
    La Plata, Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: N. Illin 1p., end. In French Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, June 8, 1897; 6-3/4x8; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends amendment to tariff bill.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 8, 1897; 8x5; Renick, E. F.
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 9, 1897; 9x7; Geological Society of London
    London, A.L.S.: L. L. Belinfante 2p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 9, 1897; 10-1/2x8; United States. Dept. of Agriculture
    Washington, Typed L.S.: L[eland] O[ssian] Howard 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 10, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Returns proofs of his paper on excavations in Florida. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, June 10, 1897; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Miller, G. A. (George Abram), 1863-1951
    Paris, A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Proofs corrected and returned.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 10, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Smith, James Perrin, 1864-1931
    Stanford University, Cal., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Has sent copy of his "Marine fossils from coal measures of Arkansas" to the Revue critique de Paléozoologie.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, June 10, 1897; 10-1/2x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington, Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: Andrew H[ussey] Allen 1p. Has no copy of pamphlet on "The definitive treaty between Great Britain and the United States...1783."
  - Letter to I[saac] Minus Hayes [sic], June 10, 1897; 11x8-1/4, 11x8-1/2, 3-3/4x6-1/4; Wilson Brothers & Co.
    Phila., L. 1p. and add. Enc. Sends estimate from Morse, Williams & Co. for dumb waiter for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to [Issac] Minis Hays, June 11, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Doolittle, C. L. (Charles Leander), 1843-1919
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Cannot recommend publication of Sajous' paper on solar heat and universal gravitation.
  - Letter to J. Minis Hayes [sic], June 11, 1897; 7x8; Edmunds, George F. (George Franklin), 1828-1919
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns his paper.
  - Letter to J[sic] M[inis] Hays, June 11, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Foote, Albert E., Co.
    Phila., Typed L. 1p., end. Can supply issues of "Insect Life."
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], June 11, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Journal of microscopy and natural science
    Bath, England, A.L.S.: Alfred Allen 1p., end. Enc. wanting Sends payment for volume of Transactions.
  - Letter to Ella [M.] Morison, June 11, 1897; 9-1/4x5-1/2; Payson, L. E. (Lewis Edwin), 1840-1909
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Concerns request for papers on petroleum
  - Letter to E[dwin] G[rant] Conklin, June 11, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Returns draft. Concerns Cope Memorial Meeting.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, June 12, 1897; 3-1/4x5-1/4; The Analyst
    Croydon, [Eng.], A.L.S.: Walter J. Sykes, on postal card 1p., end., and add. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to J. Minnis [sic] Hays, June 13, 1897; 7-1/4x4-1/2; London Mathematical Society
    Cambridge, [Eng.] A.L.S.: A[ugustus] E[dward] H[ough] Love 2p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 14, 1897; 3-1/4x5-1/4; Geological Society of London
    London, A.L.S.: L. L. Belinfante, on postal card 1p. and add. Sending publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 14, 1897; 10-1/2x7-3/4; Garrett, John Biddle
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. As executor will deal with matter concerning Cope's estate.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], June 14, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Scottish microscopical soc. Edinburgh
    Edinburgh, A.L.S.: E. Wace Carlier 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 14, 1897; 7-3/4x5; Smith, Elder, and Co.
    [London], L. 1p. Sends copy of Armstrong's Electric movements in air and water.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 14, 1897; 11-1/2x9, 6x3-1/4; Western Reserve Historical Society
    Cleveland, O., A.L.S.: Peter Neff 1p. Enc. of 4p. printed leaflet. Thanks for pamphlet on petroleum.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 15, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Royal Entomological Society of London
    London, A.L.S.: A. C. Champion 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [George Franklin] Edmunds, June 15, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. with Edmunds' reply Inquires about his paper on international arbitration.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays:, June 16, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Hopes to return proofs soon. Refers to J.C. Morris, E. Morison.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 16, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Wishard, G. W.
    Lebanon, O., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for APS report on universal language.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 17, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.] L. 1p. Appoints Prime, Hays and Ingham to committee. Written on verso of letter from Hays to Fraley, May 25, 1897.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morrison [sic], June 17, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
    Cape May, N.J., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Send membership list to Redpath Lyceum Bureau.
  - Letter to the Redpath Lyceum Bureau, June 17, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns arrangements for Nansen's appearance before A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 17, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Institution of Electrical Engineers
    London, Typed L.S.: F[rancis] W[illiam] Webb 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to E[dwin] G[rant] Conklin, June 17, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns Cope Memorial Meeting. Refers to H. Allen.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 17, 1897; 9x 5-3/4; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    Phila., Typed L.S. with MS. addition 1p. Concerns Cope Memorial Meeting.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, June 17, 1897; 8x5; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington, A.L.S.: Andrew H[ussey] Allen 2p. Thanks for pamphlet, "Definitive treaty between U.S. and Great Britain, 1783."
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, June 18, 1897; 10-1/4x8; Institution of Engineers and Shipbuilders in Scotland
    Glasgow, A.L.S.: Edward H. Parker 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], June 18, 1897; 8x5-1/2; Royal Numismatic Society (Great Britain)
    London, A.L.S.: B[arclay] V[incent] Head 1p. Cannot exchange publications.
  - Letter to MaCalla & co., Phila., June 19, 1897; 8x5; Beebe, William Sully, 1841-1898
    Thompson, Conn. A.L.S. 2p. Inquires about Brinton's paper. "The native calendar of Central America and Mexico." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 31, pp. 258-314.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 19, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922
    Stanford University, Cal., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns illustrations for Ashley's paper on the geology of Arkansas. Submits Drake's paper on the coal fields of the Indian Territory. For printed papers, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, p p.217-318, 326-419.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, June 19, 1897; 7-1/4x8-1/2; Globe Company (Cincinnati, Ohio)
    Cincinnati, Typed L. 1p. Business appointment.
  - Letter to I[saac] M[inis] Hays, June 19, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Redpath Lyceum Bureau
    Boston, Typed L. 1p. Arrangements for Nansen meeting.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 20, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Robinson, Herman Foster
    New York, A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Asks for copy of Moncure Robinson's obituary of Michel Chevalier. For printed obituary, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 19, pp. 28-37.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 21, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 3p. Is correcting proofs of his paper on excavations in Florida. Refers to Pepper. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 21, 1897; 9-3/4x8-1/4; Literary and Philosophical Society of Manchester
    A.L.S.: Cha[rle]s [William Edward] Leigh 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, June 21, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Redpath Lyceum Bureau
    Chicago, Typed L. 1p. Concerns Nansen lecture.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, June 22, 1897; 10x8, 3-1/2x6; Globe Company (Cincinnati, Ohio)
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. and add. Estimate for stacks.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 22, 1897; 9-1/4x8-1/2; Redpath Lyceum Bureau
    Boston, Typed L. 1p., end. Concerns Nansen lecture.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, June 23, 1897; 12-3/4x8, 4x9; Grigg, T. H.
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. and add. Estimates on shelving and cabinets.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 23, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Royal Photographic Society of Great Britain
    London, L.S.: R. Child Bayley 2p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to J[sic] Minis Hays, June 23, 1897; 11-1/4x8-1/2; Snyder, Monroe Benjamin, 1848-1932
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Advises strongly against publication of Sajous' paper on solar heat and universal gravitation.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 23, 1897; 10-1/2x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Thanks for pamphlet, "Definitive treaty between Great Britain and U.S. ...1783."
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 24, 1897; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Brooke, Francis M.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns Weedon's Orderly Book. Refers to Valley Forge Commission.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, June 24, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Consaul, Charles H.
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 24, 1897; 9-1/2x6; A.C. McClurg & Co.
    Chicago, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p., end. Payment for book order.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 24, 1897; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Printed L.filled in in MS. 1p. Concerns Bolton's Catalogue of Scientific and Technical Periodicals.
  - Letter to J. Minis Hayes [sic], June 26, 1897; 9-1/2x6; Ingham, William A. (William Armstrong), 1827-1913
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Angry letter about appointment to Committee on Indexing Scientific Literature.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, June 26, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Natural history society of Glasgow
    Glasgow, L. 2p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 28, 1897; 9x5-3/4; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., L. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends letter from William S. Beebe. For enclosure, see Beebe to MacCalla, June 19, 1897.
  - Letter to [William S. Beebe], June 28, 1897; 7-3/4x5; Morison, Ella M.
    Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Copy Answers question about Brinton's paper, "The native calendar of Central America and Mexico." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 31, pp. 258-314.
  - Letter to [William Armstrong] Ingham, June 28, 1897; 5x7-3/4; Morison, Ella M.
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Copy Reply to his letter about appointment to Committee on Indexing Scientific Literature, June 26, 1897. Refers to F. Prime.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], June 29, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Taussig, George W.
    St. Louis, Mo., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 29, 1897; 8x5; Prime, Frederick, 1846-1915
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Concerns papers by Sajous and d'Auria. Refers to Horn.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, June 30, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Globe Company (Cincinnati, Ohio)
    New York, Typed L. 1p. Estimate for stacks.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, June 30, 1897; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    London, A.L.S. 4p. Rebinding of Leeds 1729 Almanac by Ellis & Elvey. Refers to Jubilee, French exchanges, Ashburnham sales, John Thomson.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 1, 1897; 7-1/4x8-1/2; American Baptist Publication Society
    Chicago, Typed L. 1p., end. Inquires about cost of Transactions.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, July 1, 1897; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922
    Stanford University, Cal., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns Ashley's paper on geology of Arkansas, Drake's on the coal fields of the Indian Territory. For printed papers, see: APS proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 217-318, 326-419.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 3, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Phillips, Francis C. (Francis Clifford), 1850-1920
    Allegheny, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. Refers to Sadtler and papers on petroleum. See: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 92-140.
  - Letter to I[saac] M[inis] Hays, July 5, 1897; 8x5; British Astronomical Association
    London, A.L.S.: Tho[ma]s Frid Maunder 2p., end. Will exchange publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 5, 1897; 9-1/4x7-1/2; British Museum
    London, Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: E[dward] Maunde Thompson 1p. Sends selection of publications.
  - Letter to Frederick Traley [sic], July 5, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Foster, Roger, 1857-1924
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 5, 1897; 8x5; Society of Chemical Industry (Great Britain)
    London, A.L.S.: Chas. G. Cresswell 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, July 5, 1897; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Thompson, Edward Maunde, Sir, 1840-1929
    London, A.L.S. 2p., end. Sends British Museum publications.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hayes [sic], July 5, [1897]; 7x4-1/2; Henderson, Lucia Tiffany
    Jamestown, N.Y., A.L.S. 4p. Applies for a position. Names Mayer Sulzberger as reference.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, July 6, 1897; 5-1/2x8; Douglass, Joseph H. (Joseph Henry), 1871-1935
    Cape May, N.J., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 6, 1897; 3x4-3/4; Federated Institution of Mining Engineers (Great Britain)
    Newcastle-upon-Tyne, [Eng.] Typed L. on postal card, S.: M. W[alton] B[rown] 1p. and add. Will lay A.P.S. letter before Council.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, July 6, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Hall, Thomas B.
    Camden, N.J., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, July 6, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    Beesly's A.L.S. 1p. Arranges to sign diplomas. Asks him to visit.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 6, 1897; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Naturforschende gesellschaft zu Freiburg i. B.
    Freiburg, Printed L. on postal card, filled in in MS., S.: Gerhardt 1p., end., and add. In German Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 6, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; New York Public Library
    New York, Typed L.S.: J[ohn] S[haw] Billings 1p. Concerns missing issue of Proceedings.
  - Letter to J. Minus [sic] Hays, July 6, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Redpath Lyceum Bureau
    Boston, Typed L. 1p. Concerns Nansen lecture.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 7, 1897; 10x8, 3/4x6-1/2; Library Bureau
    Phila., Typed L. 2p., end. and add. Estimate on shelving.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, July 8, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Harvey, Oscar Jewell, 1851-
    Wilkesbarré, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns his examination of documents.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, July 8, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Hobart, George S.
    Marlboro, N.J., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, July 8, 1897; 9x5-3/4; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., A.L.S.: W[illiam] A. Pickell, Sec'y 2p. Concerns galleys of Ashley's paper. Memorial Volume I.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, July 8, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Redpath Lyceum Bureau
    Boston, Typed L. 2p. Concerns Nansen lecture.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, July 8, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Watson, William W.
    Passaic, N.J., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 10, 1897; 11-1/4x9; Verein für geographie und statistik, Frankfurt am Main
    Frankfurt am Main, Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: [Friedrich Clemens] Ebrard 1p., end. by Frazer Asks for Proceedings, No. 153.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, July 12, 1897; 10-1/4x8; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Will attend committee meeting.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, July 12, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Stewart, Ardemus
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 12, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Van Denburgh, John, 1872-1924
    San Francisco, Cal., A.L.S. 1p., end. Is sending paper on Gila monster. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 19, pp. 199-220.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 13, 1897; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Spon & Chamberlain
    New York, L. 1p., end. Asks about L.M. Haupt's paper on "The dynamic action of the ocean..." For Printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 26, pp. 146-171.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, July 13, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Woods Hole (Mass.)
    Woods Holl, Mass., A.L.S.: S. Emma Keith 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 14, 1897; 8x5; Alve, Clarence
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends report and sketches of his experiments with magnetism.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, July 14, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Davis, Francis B.
    Woodbury, N.J., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 14, 1897; 8-1/4x5; West of Scotland Iron and Steel Institute
    Glasgow, A.L.S.: T. F. Barbour, Secretary 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to E[dwin] G[rant] Conklin, July 16, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns Cope Memorial Meeting. Refers to I.M. Hays.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, July 19, 1897; 6x8; Ashley, Geo. H. (George Hall), b. 1866
    Indianapolis, Ind., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for separates of his paper on the geology of Arkansas. Refers to Branner. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings Vol. 36, pp. 217-318.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 19, 1897; 6-1/4x4; Fowler, James
    Kingston, Canada, A.L.S. 2p. Concerns Botanical Society of Canada. Refers to G. Lawson.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 20, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Canadian Institute (1849-1914)
    Toronto, A.L.S.: M. J. Logan, on postal card 1p. and add. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, July 21, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    [Phila.,] A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Sends diplomas.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, July 21, [1897]; 11x8-1/2; Redpath Lyceum Bureau
  - Letter to F. de P. Castell, July 22, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Morison, Ella M.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his request for Brinton's paper, "Grammar of the Cakchiquel language of Guatemala," in APS Proceedings, vol. 21, pp. 345-412. Written on verso is Castell to [Morison, Aug., 1897].
  - Letter to [James Cheston Morris], July 23, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
    Phila., A.L. on postal card S. 1p., end., and add. Concerns herbaria.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, July 23, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Stockhausen, P. C.
    Phila., L. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends bill. Refers to Price.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, July 24, 1897; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerns diplomas. Refers to Frazer.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 24, 1897; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Trinity College (Dublin, Ireland)
    Dublin, A.L.S.: Alfred de Burgh 2p., end. Concerns Royal Geological Society of Ireland.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, July 24, [1897]; 11x8-1/2; Redpath Lyceum Bureau
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, July 25, 1897; 6x4; Edmunds, George F. (George Franklin), 1828-1919
    Bay Head, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Endorses nomination of G.W. Pepper for membership.
  - Letter to I[saac] M[inis] Hayes [sic], July 26, 1897; 10x8-1/4; Library Bureau
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Measurements for special folio cabinet.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 27, 1897; 10x8; Royal Statistical Society (Great Britain)
    London, L.S.: Stephen Massingberd 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, July 27, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Wrifford, Charles & Son
    Phila., L. 1p. Carpentry work.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, July 28, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Sending galleys of his paper on excavations in Florida. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, July 28, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Redpath Lyceum Bureau
    Boston, Typed L. 1p. Concerns Nansen lecture. Refers to Dr. Pepper.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, July 28, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Spohr, J. R.
    Hoboken, N.J., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hayes [sic], July 30, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Sanderson, John H., & bro.
    Phila., L. 1p. Estimate on recovering armchair.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, July 30, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Tobias, John J.
    Chicago, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting Asks for copies of Phillips prize essays on "The State."
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, July 31, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Harvey, Oscar Jewell, 1851-
    Wilkesbarré, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Makes appointment to see documents of Susquehanna Company.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Aug. 1, 1897; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Dawson, George Ellsworth, 1861-1936
    Chicago, A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Aug. 2, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Carey, Francis King, 1858-1944
    Baltimore, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 3, 1897; 11-1/4x8-1/2; S.S. McClure Company (New York, N.Y.)
    New York, L. 1p. Inquires about A.P.S. publications on Babylonian excavations. Refers to Hilprecht.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 4, 1897; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Baer & co., Joseph
    Frankfurt a.M., L. on postal card 1p. and add. Asks about Proceedings.
  - Letter to O [sic] Minis Hays, Aug. 4, 1897; 6-1/2x5; Harvey, Oscar Jewell, 1851-
    Wilkesbarré, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns appointment to work in library.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, Aug. 5, 1897; 3-1/2x4-1/2; Society of Chemical Industry (Great Britain)